The 24th IEEE Real-Time and Embedded Technology and Applications Symposium (RTAS 2018)
April 11-13, 2018
Porto, Portugal

http://rtas.org/

**** Submission Deadline: October 6, 2017 (FIRM) ****

Call for Papers
============================

RTAS'18, the 24th in a series of annual conferences sponsored by the IEEE, will be held in Porto, Portugal, as part of the Cyber-Physical Systems Week (CPSWeek) in April, 2018.

Expanded scope: RTAS aims to become the premier conference venue for publishing systems research related to timing issues. The broad scope of RTAS'18 ranges from traditional hard real-time systems to latency-sensitive systems with soft real-time requirements.

RTAS'18 invites papers describing original systems and applications, case studies, methodologies and applied algorithms that contribute to the state of practice in the design, implementation and verification of real-time systems. Papers in the broader field of embedded, networked and cyber-physical systems (including but not limited to emerging domains such as Internet-of-Things (IoT), real-time cloud computing, embedded security, and heterogeneous systems) that consider real-time aspects are welcomed. For submissions to be in scope for RTAS'18, the work must consider some form of real-time requirements; as well as classical hard real-time constraints, these may be in the form of probabilistic, soft real-time, quality of service or latency requirements. The scope of RTAS'18 consists of three tracks: 
  
- Track 1: Applications, Real-Time Operating Systems and Run-Time Software;
- Track 2: Applied Methodologies and Foundations; 
- Track 3: Architectures and Hardware-related Analyses for Real-Time and Embedded Systems. 

Details of the requirements that each track places on submitted papers can be found on the conference website. The conference proceedings will be published by IEEE and indexed on IEEE Explore. 

Paper Submission Guidelines 
============================
 
All papers must be submitted electronically in PDF format, following the IEEE conference proceedings format. The main body of each submitted paper is limited to 10 pages of technical content with additional pages permitted for the bibliography and acknowledgments only. Additionally, each submission may include an optional appendix with supplemental material that will be read at the discretion of the program committee; this appendix is limited to two pages (for up to 12 pages total of technical content, i.e., content not including the bibliography and acknowledgements). Details of the submission process can be found on the conference website.

Important Dates
============================

Submission Deadline: Oct 6, 2017 11:59pm (UTC-12) - firm
Author Rebuttal: Nov 25 - Dec 1, 2017
Notifications: Dec 19, 2017

Organizers
============================

General Chair:
Gabriel Parmer
The George Washington University, USA

Program Chair and Track 1 Chair:
Rodolfo Pellizzoni
University of Waterloo, Canada

Track 2 Chair:
Linh Thi Xuan Phan 
University of Pennsylvania, USA

Track 3 Chair:
Nan Guan
Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Hong Kong
