Call for Papers and Announcement
ACSD 2019
19th INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON APPLICATION OF CONCURRENCY TO SYSTEM DESIGN
Aachen, Germany, June 23-28, 2019

Additional information about the conference will be published via http://www.petrinets2019.de/acsd-2019/

The conference will be co-located with the 40th International Conference on Applications and Theory of Petri Nets and Concurrency (Petri Nets 2019).


IMPORTANT DATES:
Abstract submission: January 16, 2019 (*)
Submission of Papers: January 22, 2019 (*)
Notification: March 8, 2019
Final Version Due: March 22, 2019 (*)
Participation in Tool Exhibition: June 1, 2019
Conference: June 23-28, 2019
(*) The deadline is the end of day Anywhere on Earth (AoE)

The 19th international ACSD conference will be organized by the Process and Data Science (PADS) group at RWTH Aachen University, Aachen, Germany. The new PADS group was established in the context of Wil van der Aalst’s Alexander von Humboldt Professorship. The conference will take place in the conference area of the Tivoli football stadium close to the city center of Aachen. The language of the conference is English, and the conference proceedings will be submitted for inclusion to IEEE Xplore.


CONFERENCE SCOPE:
The conference aims at cross-fertilizing both theoretical and applied research about formal approaches (in a broad sense) to designing computer systems that exhibit some kind of concurrent behavior. In particular, the following topics are of interest:
- Formal models of computation and concurrency for the above systems and problems, like data- flow models, communicating automata, Petri nets, process algebras, graph rewriting systems, state charts, MSCs, modal and temporal logics
- Compositional design principles like modular synthesis, distributed simulation and implementation, distributed control, adaptivity, supervisory control
- Algorithms and tools for concurrent systems, ranging from programming languages to algorithmic methods for system analysis and construction, including model checking, verification, and static analysis techniques as well as synthesis procedures
- Synchronous and asynchronous systems on all design levels: polychronous systems, endochronous systems, globally asynchronous locally synchronous systems
- Cyber-physical systems, hybrid systems, networked systems, and networks in biological systems
- High-performance computer architectures like many-core processors, networks on chip, graphics processing units, instruction-level parallelism, dataflow architectures, up to ad-hoc, mobile, and wireless networks
- Memory consistency models for multiprocessor and multicore architectures, replicated data, including software and hardware memory models, DRAM scheduling, cache coherency, memory-aware algorithms
- Real-time aspects, including hard real-time requirements, security and safety-critical issues, functional and timing verification
- Implementation aspects like resource management, including task and communication scheduling, network-, memory-, and power-management, energy/power distribution, fault-tolerance, quality of service, scalability, load balancing, power proportionality
- Design principles for concurrent systems, in particular hardware/software co-design, platform-based design, component-based design, energy-aware design, refinement techniques, hardware/software abstractions, cross-layer optimization
- Business process modelling, workflow execution systems, process (de-)composition, inter-organizational and heterogeneous workflow systems, systems for computer-supported collaborative work, web services
- Case studies of general interest, from industrial applications to consumer electronics and multimedia, automotive systems, (bio-)medical applications, neuromorphic applications, internet (of things) and grid computing, to gaming applications.


PAPER SUBMISSION:
ACSD seeks papers describing original work which has not been previously published and is not under review for publication elsewhere. All files must be prepared using the latest IEEE Computer Society conference proceedings guidelines (8.5” × 11” two-column format). The page limit for regular papers is 10 pages. Accepted papers will be included in the conference proceedings. At least one author of each accepted contribution is expected to present the paper at the conference, and will be required to sign the copyright release forms. All papers have to be submitted via EasyChair: https://easychair.org/conferences/?conf=acsd2019.


ORGANIZATION

Program Committee Co-chairs
Jörg Keller
University of Hagen,
Faculty of Mathematics and
Computer Science
Germany
Joerg.Keller@fernuni-hagen.de

Wojciech Penczek
Institute of Computer Science PAS,
University of Natural Sciences and
Humanities
Poland
w.penczek@ipipan.waw.pl

General Chair
Wil van der Aalst
Process and Data Science (PADS)
RWTH Aachen University
52074 Aachen, Germany
wvdaalst@pads.rwth-aachen.de

Steering Committee
Alex Yakovlev, UK (chair)
Benoit Caillaud, France
Jordi Cortadella, Spain
Jörg Desel, Germany
Alex Kondratyev, USA
Luciano Lavagno, Italy
Antti Valmari, Finland
Andrey Mokhov, UK

Organizing Committee
Wil van der Aalst (general chair)
Anna Kalenkova (publicity chair)
Detlef Wetzler (web chair)

Program Committee
S. Akshay, India
Étienne André, France
Mohamed Faouzi Atig, Sweden
Josep Carmona, Spain
Franck Cassez, Australia
Thomas Chatain, France
Rocco De Nicola, Italy
Jörg Desel, Germany
Klaus Echtle, Germany
Alain Girault, France
Radu Grosu, Austria
Stefan Haar, France
Loïc Hélouët, France
Ludovic Henrio, France
Loïg Jézéquel, France
Gabriel Juhás, Slovakia
Marta Pietkiewicz-Koutny, UK
Jörg Keller, Germany (co-chair)
Christoph Kessler, Sweden
Jan Křetínský, Czech Republic
Johan Lilius, Finland
Gerald Lüttgen, Germany
Roland Meyer, Germany
Andrey Mokhov, UK
Claire Pagetti, France
Wojciech Penczek, Poland (co-chair)
Laure Petrucci, France
Dumitru Potop-Butucaru, France
Klaus Schneider, Germany
Sandeep Shukla, India
Ashutosh Trivedi, India
Jaco van de Pol, Denmark
Fei Xia, UK


AACHEN
Aachen is a historic city in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany, at the point where Germany borders on Belgium and the Netherlands. Historically this spa-town was a prominent city, the place where the German Kings were crowned, and the residence of Charlemagne who still lies buried in the impressive cathedral he himself had built. The city has many historical sites that remind of those days, including medieval buildings, city gates, and beautiful fountains. Aachen is Germany’s westernmost city. It lies near the borders with Belgium and the Netherlands and is nestled between the large national parks of the Eifel and the Ardennes. The city has a population of 260,000, which includes about 50,000 students and more than 4,000 academic staff from across the world. Its lively student community lends the city just as much character as its history. Aachen is famous for its Printen gingerbread, its hot springs, its Mardi Gras carnival and one of the world’s largest equestrian tournaments. The historic city center and a wealth of bars, cafés, and restaurants, combined with the nearby nature parks, such as the Eifel, make Aachen a city where everyone feels at home. The venue of the conference, the Tivoli football stadium, is located on the border of the city center. This beautiful venue will provide a unique atmosphere with great views and excellent conference facilities.